ROMAN KOLGUSHEV

kolgushev@gmail.com | +1 (415) 625-0566 RomanKolgushev.com | github.com/kgshv

RÉSUMÉ

SKILLS



Web design and development

5+ years of experience with HTML5, CSS3 (LESS) and JavaScript.

Working knowledge of JS frameworks and libraries:

- * jQuery
- * Angular JS
- * D3
- * HighCharts
- * Leaflet
- * MapBox
- + many others

Developed stand-alone and integrated web applications, build and maintained WordPress themes (some plugins), maintained websites with 500,000+ monthly page views.

Latest works include:

https://siliconvalley.tours (theme, much of the functionality, most front-end and back-end code)

http://www.hinocanada.com/ (was involved in website design and development)

https://biz30.timedoctor.com/rise-of-slack-death-of-skype/

Back-end and scripting

4+ years of experience with Python including multiple libraries and frameworks:

- * Flask
- * Django
- * Peewee
- * Mechanize
- * BeautifulSoup
- + others

Developed projects raging in scale from web scrapers and scripts to an online assignment management tool featuring social media authentication, user roles management & internal messaging.

2+ years of experience with PHP & WordPress dev:

Built themes and plugins for end users, currently maintain several WP websites for clients.

Database analysis, design & formatting

4+ years of experience designing and working with DB architecture using MySQL and sqlite, have some MongoDB experience.

Experienced user of MySQL through interactive interfaces (phpMyAdmin, NaviCAT, MySQL Workbench), directly via command line interface, in Python using ORM approach (peewee, SQLAlchemy) and via PHP.

UI/UX design and other skills

5+ years of experience in hands-on wireframing and UX testing, I build all web apps following responsive design guidelines and QA best practices.

Experienced user of:
* Git version control system.

- * Amazon AWS
- * JSON standards
- * AJAX logic and framework
- * Linux systems (LAMP stack included)
- * Google Analytics (including API)
- * Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

Have working knowledge of:

- * mercurial version control system
- * QGIS
- * Mixpanel (including API)
- * APIs: WordPress REST; Mailchimp; OptInMonster; Google Maps, Docs, Sheets and many others.

1

ROMAN KOLGUSHEV

kolgushev@gmail.com | +1 (415) 625-0566 RomanKolgushev.com | github.com/kgshv

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2018 - currently	Self-employed • Work remotely with several clients providing database analysis, WordPress management and development (full-stack),web design and dataviz services.
June 2017 - July 2018	 Lead full-stack developer for new projects, Silicon Valley Innovation Center (full-time remote) Helped set up multiple new WordPress websites Developed WP themes and plugins for internal use, full stack Developed strategy for solving complicated problems, developed and implemented software solutions. Completely self-managed
Sept 2016 - June 2017	 Front End Developer, tbk Creative (London, ON, Canada) Worked daily with a team of developers on an array of WordPress websites as front end developer Followed strict pixel-perfect design rules Tracked all work time and submitted daily written progress reports
Aug 2015 – Sept 2016	 Head of Newsroom Digital Innovation, <u>KyivPost.com</u> Development of data-driven journalistic projects and applications Oversight of new website development Management of old current web site source code, updating the website Production of interactive graphics and visualizations
Jan 2016 – June 2016, Jan 2018 - May 2018	Instructor of Data Journalism and Infographics, National University of Kyiv-Mohyla Academy School of Journalism, Kyiv • Developed the syllabus and curriculum, taught class to senior students
July 2014 - Aug 2015	 Data Editor / Teaching Assistant, ColumbiaMissourian.com Developed data-based web applications Produced Information graphics (static & interactive) Managed the graphics desk / taught graphics production Managed the website source code & performed troubleshooting Did database management and data migration
June 2013 - July 2014	Research Assistant, DocumentCloud.org Developed the DocumentCloud mobile viewer software code base Translated of the platform into Ukrainian and Russian Platformed user analytics analysis
Jun 2013 - Aug 2013	Graphics Internship, MissouriBusinessAlert.com • Produced interactive and static infographics on a daily basis • Helped develop the publication unified online design style
Sept 2005 - Aug 2011	Reporter, editor, various publications • Worked as a reporter and editor in multiple news organizations in Ukraine

LATEST & MAJOR PROJECTS - SEE MORE AT ROMANKOLGUSHEV.COM

Silicon Valley Tours Website	 Wordpress website theme adjustments, plugin dev / full stack Oversaw the digital evolution of the Silicon Valley Tours Website in its initial stage. Made decisions concerning backend architecture and functionality, developed back-end and front-end code, did theme and plugin, server maintenance. Was responsible for quality assurance and security. Project URL: https://siliconvalley.tours
The Rize of Slack and the Death of Skype	 Interactive Story based on a database research Analyzed several-billion-records database, provided by Time Doctor, a time tracking service. Using my research findings developed an interactive story web app, alongside writing all the copy for it. Wrote a Wordpress plugin to allow publishing of the story on the TimeDoctor blog. Project URL: https://biz3o.timedoctor.com/rise-of-slack-death-of-skype
Smarty	 A Google Analytics Slack bot for the newsroom Smarty was built for the Kyiv Post newsroom, made open source. It integrates into a Slack account and can tell you all kinds of things about how your articles are performing. Project URL: https://github.com/kgshv/smarty
Graphics Manager	 An assignment management tool, was used daily in the Columbia Missourian newsroom (no longer maintained now). Built from ground up with Flask (Python), features Google Plus authentication, user roles management, internal messaging, much more. Project demo video URL: http://y2u.be/FZPGrLQN_6s

EDUCATION

2012-2014	 Master of Arts, University of Missouri School of Journalism, Missouri, USA Study emphases: computer assisted reporting, data journalism, computer programming, graphic and web design, quantitative and qualitative research.
2009 - 2010	Convergence journalism program in Kyiv (Ukraine) from National University of Kyiv-Mohyla Academy School of Journalism
2005-2010	Bachelor's and Master's degree in Theory of Translation, Donetsk National University, Ukraine. • Study emphases: theory and practice of translation, comparative grammar and lexicology, English and German languages